icelolly.com 2018-09-06

# Our Privacy Policy | icelolly.com

_Last updated: 22nd May 2018_

This Policy explains when and why we collect Personal Data about the people who visit our website or other platforms such as, mobile applications, email, text messages, chatbots and social media accounts (“Platforms”), how we use such data, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you are happy with any changes. We will notify you of any material changes on how we use your Personal Data prior to implementing them. Notification of any such material change will be made by email or prominent notice on our website. By using our Platforms, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy.

This Policy is produced in accordance with applicable data protection laws including European General Data Protection Regulation (EU 2016/679) (“GDPR”).

This Policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below.

Who are we?

Your choices and right to withdraw consent.

Your Rights

The types of data we collect

How we collect your Personal Data

Why we collect your Personal Data

Purposes for which we use your Personal Data

How we share your Personal Data

How we store and protect your Personal Data

How long we keep your Personal Data

Cookies, tracking tools and profiling

Third-party websites

## Who are we?

We are Icelolly Marketing Limited (icelolly.com, or we or us), a company incorporated and registered in England and Wales (company number 05655962), whose registered office is at 19 – 20 Park Row House, Park Row, Leeds LS1 5JF. We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

The Company is a data controller of your Personal Data collected via the Platforms.

Contact Us

If you would like any more information or you have any comments or enquiries about our Policy or our processing of your Personal Data, please either write to us at Data Protection Manager, Icelolly Marketing Limited, 19-20 Park Row House, Park Row, Leeds LS1 5JF, or email us at [data.protection@icelolly.com](http://data.protection@icelolly.com/).

## Your choices and right to withdraw consent

When you first give us Personal Data through our Platforms, we will ask for your consent to contact you about our services, and those of our partners who provide services featured or included on our Websites or Platforms (“Partners”).

Where we rely on your consent to process your Personal Data for a particular purpose, we will not process your Personal Data for that purpose without your consent.

You can withdraw consent at any time for us to process your Personal Data to direct market to you by; (i) clicking UNSUBSCRIBE or other opt-out urls on any marketing email you receive from us (ii) clicking the unsubscribe link. <https://www.icelolly.com/emailoffers/unsubscribe>

## Your Rights

### Subject Access Requests

You are entitled at any time to obtain information about all your Personal Data that we hold about you, in accordance with the Act. We may request proof of your identity before providing this information and may not be able to allow you to access certain Personal Data in some cases. For example, if your Personal Data is connected with Personal Data of other persons, or for legal reasons. In such cases we will provide you with an explanation why you cannot obtain this information.

If you would like access to the Personal Data that we hold about you, you can do this by emailing us at [data.protection@icelolly.com](http://data.protection@icelolly.com/) (or writing to us at the address stated above under the heading **Who Are We?** )

**_No fee usually required_**  
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal information (or to exercise any of your other data subject rights explained below). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request for access is clearly unfounded or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with the request in such circumstances.

### Updating your Personal Data

We control the processing of Personal Data on our Platforms with the aim of keeping the Personal Data we hold about you accurate and up to date. If you tell us that we are holding any inaccurate Personal Data about you we will, subject to any statutory provisions, (especially those affecting our accounting, processing of claims and mandatory data retention which may prohibit deletion or anonymization), delete it or correct it promptly.

Please email us at [data.protection@icelolly.com](http://data.protection@icelolly.com/) or write to us at the address above to correct or update your Personal Data.

### Your other rights under GDPR

Your rights are enhanced under GDPR. GDPR came into force on 25th May 2018.

Your other rights under GDPR are to:

  * **Request erasure** of your Personal Data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove Personal Data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your Personal Data where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below). 
  * **Object to processing** of your Personal Data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground. You also have the right to object where we are processing your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes. 
  * **Request the restriction of processing** of your Personal Data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of Personal Data about you, for example if you want us to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it. 
  * **Request the transfer** of your Personal Data to another party.

If you want to request erasure of your Personal Data, object to the processing of your personal data, or request that we transfer a copy of your Personal Data to another party, please contact the Data Privacy Manager at data.protection@icelolly.com.

Further information on these rights and GDPR can be found at [https://ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/).

**Right to complain:** You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk](https://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

### What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is another appropriate security measure to ensure that personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.

### Time to respond

We try to respond to all legitimate data subject requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

## The types of Personal Data we collect

When you use or visit our Platforms, we collect information from you. Some of it may be Personal Data. This information includes:

  * **Profile Data** includes your username and password, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses, support requests and responses, and (if you choose to register or login to our Platforms using your email address) your email address and password. 
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your holiday preferences. 
  * **Identity Data** includes unique username and partial post code.
  * **Contact Data** includes email address and telephone numbers.
  * **Technical Data** includes [internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, access times, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system, settings and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website screen resolution, referring URL; (If you are using a mobile device) data that identifies your device, your settings and your location. 

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences. If you do send us such personal data for any reason, we will only use it with your explicit consent for the purposes specified in your request.

When you give us Personal Data, you are telling us that the information is true, accurate, complete and current. You are also telling us that you have the authorisation to provide it to us.

If you choose to register or login to our Platforms using your email address, we may collect your email address and password. If you choose a third-party service, like Facebook login, to register or login to our Platforms, you are permitting us to use and store the profile information related to your social media account.

## How we collect your Personal Data

We collect your Personal Data:

  * **Directly from you** \- For example, when you provide us with your Personal Data when you register with or use our Platforms or use our online chat products or other services or when you otherwise interact with us. 
  * **Passively** \- For example, we collect Technical Data and information about you over time when you visit our Platforms. We also use automated technologies and tracking tools like cookies, analytical tools and beacons. Please see our cookie policy below for details. 
  * **From third parties** This can include when you log in using a third-party platform, such as Facebook, analytics providers such as Google, advertising networks such as DoubleClick & Intent Media and search information providers such as Intent Media. In the case of Intent Media who provide personalized shopping experiences and advertising and use online identifiers to identify visitors, you can review their privacy policy & options to Opt out at http://intentmedia.com/privacy-policy/. 

Platform features may make use of your device attributes and settings that will allow us to determine your physical location. Such technologies may include IP address mapping, WiFi, GPS signals, cell tower positioning or other technologies. 

## Why we collect your Personal Data

We use your Personal Data to enhance and personalise your experience and provide you with offers and services that may be of interest to you.

These can be based on your Profile Data and Marketing and Communications Data. For example, we may help you find deals flying from your closest airport or send you messages that may be of interest to you based on your current location. We may also use your Personal Data to provide the services on our website to you and as outlined in the Table below.

icelolly.com does not have control over your device settings, but we recommend enabling location services on your device so that you can take advantage of the location-based features and functionality offered.

## Purposes for which we use your Personal Data

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please Contact us ([data.protection@icelolly.com](mailto://data.protection@icelolly.com)) if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful Basis**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Contact you as follows:

  * To send alerts and notifications you have subscribed to, including to your mobile device;
  * To solicit reviews and feedback;
  * To send you marketing emails from an icelolly.com address regarding our services or those of our partners, if you have opted-in to receive emails from us. 

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Consent  
  
Store information about your preferences and so allow us to customise our Platforms according to your individual interests;

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to deliver our products and services)**  
  
Respond to a service request (via chat or other Platforms)

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to deliver our products and services)**  
  
Provide you with, or facilitate the provision of, products and services you are looking for

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to deliver our products and services; to promote and grow our business)**  
  
Process data to understand the users of our Platforms and services, and improve our Platforms and services.

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to deliver our products and services; to promote and grow our business)**  
  
Take action to protect and prevent our tangible and intellectual property and to prevent damage to them.

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to take steps to protect our assets and commercial interests from theft or exploitation; to prevent fraud)**  
  
Display more relevant advertising and recommendations or suppress advertising and content that you might find irrelevant.

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to deliver our products and services; to promote and grow our business)**  
  
Estimate our audience size and usage pattern;

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(due diligence and corporate operations and planning)**  
  
To speed up your searches;

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to manage and improve our services)**  
  
To recognise you when you return to our Platforms.

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
Legitimate interest   
**(to manage and improve our services)**  
  
To ensure network, information and system security, including testing and development of IT systems

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)   
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To participate and comply with industry watch-lists and industry self-regulatory schemes

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business, for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security)   
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To carry out corporate operations and due diligence (reporting of management information, operation of financial/risk/credit models, back office operation, managing third party service providers, corporate reorganisations, corporate or asset sales)

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise, investment or sale of business)   
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To report potential crimes to relevant authorities

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security)   
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To detect and prevent fraud and crime

|  | Profile  
---  
Usage  
Marketing and Communications  
Identity  
Contact  
Technical  
  
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security)   
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
Personal Data about our customers is an important part of our business and we shall only use your Personal Data for the above purposes and shall not keep such Personal Data longer than is necessary to fulfil these purposes.

## How we share your Personal Data

We will not share your Personal Data with third parties except with your consent or as otherwise permitted or required by applicable laws including and subject to GDPR. 

**Partners:** We may need to share your Personal Data with our travel Partners, for example, any feedback on their services, in which case we will obtain your consent before we do so.

**Promotions/Competitions:** We may share your Personal Data as otherwise described and notified to you at the time of collection. For example, if you provide your Personal Data to enter a competition, we may share your Personal Data with promotional or business partners for the purposes of entering such competition.

**Sale or Reorganisations:** In in the event of a sale of our business, or a reorganisation of our business, or as otherwise required by law or applicable regulator, we may transfer your Personal Data to third parties (as part of the information generally contained in business) but such transferred data would be subject to this Policy and will not be transferred unless the recipient can commit to keep your Personal Data secure and in accordance with applicable privacy laws.

**Reviews:** If you provide a review of your trip via our website or on a linked website, you will be required to authorise us to publish it on all our Platforms under the screen name you provided on our website or the linked website. You also authorise us to aggregate it with other reviews.

**As required by law:** We may disclose Personal Data if required by law, for example to law enforcement or other authorities. This includes court orders, subpoenas and orders arising from legal processes, and administrative or criminal investigations. We may also disclose your Personal Data if the disclosure is necessary for the prevention, detection or prosecution of criminal acts or to prevent other damage, or in response to a legal action or to enforce our rights and claims.

**Service providers:** We may share with service providers who acting as processors provide IT, hosting and system administration services.

**Group companies:** We may disclose your Personal Data to any member of our group of companies, which means any subsidiary or holding company of icelolly.com and a "subsidiary" includes a "subsidiary" and a "subsidiary undertaking" (each as defined in the Companies Act 2006) and a "holding company" includes a "holding company" and a "parent undertaking" (each as defined in the Companies Act 2006). We will do so under strict conditions of confidentiality.

**Children:** We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from minors (persons under the age of 18 years). If we become aware that a minor is attempting to submit Personal Data, we will remove this Personal Data from our records. If you are the parent/legal guardian of a minor who has given us Personal Data, please contact us immediately at data.Protection@icelolly.com so we can delete it.

We may also share anonymous aggregated usage information with others.

## How we store and protect your Personal Data

Our servers and data centres are located in the European Union (EU). However, we may need to transfer your Personal Data to staff operating outside the European Economic Area (EEA) who work for us or for one of our Partners. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. These countries may have different and/or less stringent privacy/data protection and data security rules than those of the UK and EU. We will take all steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy.

If we need to transfer your Personal Data outside the EEA to a third party (for example, one of our travel Partners) or to one of our group companies, we will satisfy at least one of the following conditions:

  * use specific contracts (between us and the recipient organisation) approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries; or 
  * obtain your explicit consent to the transfer prior to the transfer after making you aware of the risks involved in such transfers; 
  * only transfer if necessary pursuant to a contract between the data controller and you (or pre-contractual measures at your request); 

If we need to transfer your Personal Data outside the EEA to another of our group companies, we may, as an alternative to the above three conditions, use Binding Corporate rules. For further details, see European Commission: Binding corporate rules.

We have a security program designed to keep the Personal Data stored in our systems protected from unauthorised access and misuse. Personal Data may only be accessed by persons within our organisation or Partners to carry out the uses indicated in this Policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website and other Platforms via the internet; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your Personal Data, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**Internet**

Please note that communications over the internet, such as emails and webmails (messages sent through a website), are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before they are delivered – this is the nature of the internet. We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of Personal Data that is beyond our control. You are encouraged not to include any sensitive or Special Category data in your communications with us.

## How long we keep your Personal Data

We will only keep your Personal Data for the purposes outlined in this Policy and when these purposes have expired, or are no longer relevant, or you have withdrawn your consent for us to use your Personal Data (and we have no other lawful basis to use such data), we will delete such data. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. In the meantime, we will continue to use your Personal Data to contact you in the manner set out in this Policy or otherwise for the purposes set out in this Policy. If you have any questions regarding data retention periods please contact us at [data.protection@icelolly.com](mailto://data.protection@icelolly.com)

**IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA**

Where we need to collect personal data required by law or required to provide a service you have requested, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to provide you with the services requested. 

## Cookies, tracking tools and profiling

### Cookies

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. This sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your computer’s hard drive that records how you’ve used a website. These are called ‘cookies’. These cookies cannot be used to identify you personally and are used to improve services for you. So, for example, the next time you visit that website, it can tailor your options based on the information it has stored about your last visit.

To learn more about cookies, see [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or [www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/cookies/)

To learn more about the cookies we use on our website go to www.icelolly.com/cookies

Your browser may give you the ability to control cookies. How to do this varies from browser to browser. You should view the Help menu on the browser you use for further information. By turning off cookies, you might not be able to use some of the products or services on our Platforms.

We or our third-party service providers may set and use analytics cookies. These allow us to gather aggregated or segmented information about the types of visitors that access our Platforms and the pages and advertisements that they view.

We also use data collection cookies to enhance your use of our website. These cookies are used to help us understand how you engage with the icelolly.com website so we can tailor content based on your interests.

By using the icelolly.com website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your access device.

You may not be able to use any of the above features if you set your device to block cookies, delete cookies or opt out of online behavioural advertising.

Please note that our advertisers or suppliers accessed through links displayed on our website may also use cookies, over which we have no control.

### Profiling

We may analyse your Personal Data to create a profile of your interests and preferences so that we can contact you with information relevant to you. We may make use of additional information about you when it is available from external sources to help us do this effectively. This can involve profiling, that is, automated processing of your Personal Data to determine and evaluate your preferences. You have a right to object to such profiling where we process on the basis of legitimate interest.

### Tracking tools

We, our advertisers and our business partners, use several common tracking tools on the Platforms and those platforms of our advertisers and partners. We use these tools in order to:

  * Track new visitors to our Platforms;
  * Help us recognise your browser as a previous visitor. This includes saving and remembering any preferences that may have been set while your browser was visiting our Platforms, such as language; 
  * Store your username and password if you are registered with us;
  * Work with online advertising companies to display targeted advertising on our Platforms and third-party platforms that you visit. This targeting may be based on information you submit on our Platforms or third-party platforms. This targeting may also be based on your activities or behaviours on our Platforms or those of third parties; 
  * Help improve our website offering and for capacity planning purposes. In particular, We, our advertisers and our business partners may use tracking tools such as web beacons. Web beacons are placed in the code of a web page or an email newsletter for the purpose of determining who has seen and engaged with the promotion or announcement and therefore its value to the customer and whether re-engagement is appropriate; 

We may also use Google Analytics to collect demographic and interest data about you (such as age, gender, and interests), which enables us to improve our platforms and deliver content pertinent to the visitor.

By using our Platforms, you agree to our use of the profiling and tracking tools mentioned above.

## Third-party websites

Our website and Platforms may contain links to other websites run by other organisations. This Policy applies only to our website and Platforms‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites and platforms even if you access them using links from our Platforms.

In addition, if you linked to our website from a third-party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third-party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third-party site.
